Guide to the Joshua Irving Tracey papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Joshua Irving Tracey papers
1913-1951
MS 503
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(4 boxes)
Lectures, lecture notes and examinations dating from Tracey's teaching at Yale University.
Tracey, Joshua Irving, 1883-1963
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Joshua I. Tracey (1883-1963): educator; B.S. Dickinson, 1906; Ph.D., Johns Hopkins, 1912; instructor of Mathematics, Yale, 1912-1916, assistant professor, 1916-1926, associate professor, 1926-1952, associate professor emeritus, 1952-1963.
Scope and Contents
Lectures, lecture notes and examinations dating from Tracey's teaching at Yale University.
Mathematics -- Study and teaching; Tracey, Joshua Irving, 1883-1963; Yale University -- Faculty
- Inventory
  - Lectures and notes
    - Morley- Geometry (Box 1)
    - Geometry lectures-Morley I (Box 1)
    - Geometry lectures-Morley II (Box 1)
    - Geometry lectures-Morley III (Box 1)
    - Geometry lectures-Morley IV (Box 1)
    - Geometry lectures, 1913-1914 (Box 1)
    - Advanced geometry, 1921-1923 (Box 1)
    - Lectures in modern geometry, 1935-1936 (Box 1)
    - Coble-lectures on elliptic functions-Reimann (Box 1)
    - High plane curves (Box 1)
    - Group theory (Box 1)
    - brief papers in Geometry (Box 1)
    - Geometry of space (Box 1)
    - Rational space qunitic (Box 1)
    - Advanced algebra (Box 1)
    - Cremona transformations (Box 1)
    - Modern Geometry Elem. Grad. (Box 1)
    - Differential geometry (Box 1)
    - Cohen-Theory of functions and vector analysis (Box 1)
    - Various Seminary reports (Box 1)
    - inverse geometry (Box 1)
  - Examinations, etc
    - Letters
      - JIT to/from J.R. Kline, 1936-1938 (Box 2)
      - to JIT from misc re: geometric problems (Box 2)
      - correspondence on the Mathematical Association of America program, 1944 August 12 (Box 2)
      - correspondence about the honor course in mathematics taken by a student at Wells College; honors course outline (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous
      - undergraduate instruciton in mathematics, 1937 (Box 2)
      - mimiographed set of notes to supplement material in text (Box 2)
      - lecture: the straight in space (Box 2)
      - The right spehrical triangle (Box 2)
      - drawings of geometic figures (Box 2)
    - Examinations
      - September examinations, math 11 and 12, 1934-1939 (Box 2)
      - completed exams and stencils for exams (Box 2)
      - Math 23 and 25a exams, 193901948 (Box 2)
      - Math 26 and 50 (Box 2)
      - Math 26, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
      - Math 50, 1947-1951 (Box 2)
      - preliminary, 1934-1942 (Box 2)
      - Math 26 tests, 1939-1948 (Box 2)
  - Lecutures used by JIT
    - Cable-miscellaneous lectures (Box 3)
    - Cable-lectures on transformations and number theories (Box 3)
    - Cable-lectures on the theory of correspondence (Box 3)
    - Cohen-differential geometry (Box 3)
    - Hulburt-miscellaneous lectures (Box 3)
    - Morley-inverse geometry (Box 3)
    - Morley-theory of functions (Box 3)
  - Math 12 exams, 1939-1951 (Box 4)
  - Math 11 exams, 1939 (Box 4)
  - Sophomore Barge Prize examinations, 1934-1941 (Box 4)
  - Undergraduate Mathematics Club problems (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous undated problems (Box 4)
  - Math 12 make up exam, 1938 September (Box 4)
  - Math 12 special conditions, 1949 June (Box 4)
  - Math 12 exams, 1935-1946 (Box 4)
  - Examinations fo rthe Barge, and the Hulburt and Bunk prizes (Box 4)
  - 1938 College entrance examination board test in plane trigonometry (Box 4)
  - miscellaneous tests of less dimension and stature (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous hour tests amth 12, 1948-1949 (Box 4)
  - Notes on mathematical properties
    - primitive phythagorean numbers (Box 4)
    - stereographic projection (Box 4)
    - surfaces and curves- the I2 and the conic (Box 4)
    - the involution I 2,1 (Box 4)
    - classification of quadratic surfaces (Box 4)
    - some properties of quadratic surfaces (Box 4)
  - proof pages of J.I.T's book, Analytic Geometry, chapters 2-4 (Box 4)